Guide to the Philip G. Zimbardo Papers SC0750
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Teaching files, Series 7
  - Coercion, compliance and confession. Social psychology (Box 151, Folder 19)
  - Schematic presentation of primary persuasibility profiles. Attitude change. Teaching social attitude change (Box 151, Folder 20)
  - Historical sketch of social psychology (Box 151, Folder 21)
  - Commencement, Psychology Dept., 2003 June (Box 151, Folder 22)
  - Human Subjects Committee (Box 151, Folder 23)
  - Psych 1 - Development (Box 151, Folder 24)
  - Psych 1 - The Self (Box 151, Folder 25)
  - Assertion Training (Box 151, Folder 26)
  - Psychology 101 (Box 151, Folder 27)
  - Stanford U. strike - anti-war activities, 1970 (Box 151, Folder 28)
  - Tanya's [Zimbardo] essay, 1992 (Box 151, Folder 29)
  - Glass slides (Box 16)
  - Psychology 1 syllabus, Winter 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Stanford University psychology Ph.D.'s, 1912-1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Stanford University psychology students, 1968-1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Discovering Psychology" Telecourse Brochure (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Human Subjects Requests and Approvals (Box 102, Folder 38)
- Oversized materials, Series 8
  This series contains large format transparencies, posters, promotional materials, photographs, and a psychology board game called The Monkey Game.
  - The Monkey Game-by Rick D. Potter. Includes booklet, cards, and felt board., 1977 (Box 134)
  - Transparencies-Madness & Drama (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Transparencies-Madness (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Transparencies-Madness (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Transparencies-Madness (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Transparencies-Madness (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Transparencies-Hypnosis (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Transparencies-Three Bias Study (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Transparencies-Time Perspective (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Speak Magazine, 1997 (Box 149, Folder 1)
  - Lynching (photograph) (Box 149, Folder 2)
  - Festa Della Cultura, Cammarata-San Giovanni Gemini (posters), 2009 (Box 149, Folder 3)
  - Shyness (poster and clipping) (Box 149, Folder 4)
- Restricted materials, Series 9
  The materials in this series are restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
  Materials in this series are primarily teaching files restricted due to privacy concerns protected under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Also restricted are files containing private medical or legal information and/or social security numbers.
  - Student Grades/Information
    Materials in this series are restricted due to privacy concerns related to the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Files include student numbers and/or graded coursework.
    - Mind Control-Final Grades, 1995 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - Mind Control Course (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - Psychology 199 - Final Exams, 1990 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Mind Control, 1991 (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - Psych 199-Mind Control, 1990 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - Psych 199-Mind Control, 1990 (Box 161, Folder 6)
    - Psych 199-Final Grades (Box 161, Folder 7)
    - Mind Control-Final (Box 161, Folder 8)
    - Psych 1-Exams and Grades, 2000 (Box 161, Folder 9)
    - Zim-Value of Practicum in Teaching Feedback from Grads, 2000 (Box 161, Folder 10)
    - Teaching Practicum Evaluations, 2000 (Box 161, Folder 11)
    - Interact Lab with L. Henderson, 2001 (Box 161, Folder 12)
    - Psych 1-Exams and Grades, 2001 (Box 161, Folder 13)
    - Psych 1-Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2003 (Box 161, Folder 14)
    - Psych 1-Final Grades, 1994 (Box 161, Folder 15)
    - Psych 1-Exams and Grades, 1998 (Box 161, Folder 16)
    - CV-4288 (Box 161, Folder 17)
    - Proposal for a New Graduate Core-Lab Course, 2000 (Box 161, Folder 18)
    - Psych 314 - Teaching-On Becoming a Professional Psychologist, 1981-1982 (Box 161, Folder 19)
    - Psychology 1, 1997 (Box 161, Folder 20)
    - Grades (Box 161, Folder 21)
    - Psych 1-Exams and Grades, 1999 (Box 161, Folder 22)
    - Cheating Confession (Box 161, Folder 23)
    - Psych 1-Exam 3 (Box 161, Folder 24)
    - Peer Study (Box 161, Folder 25)
    - Correlations of Exam Data (Box 161, Folder 26)
    - Peer (Box 161, Folder 27)
    - Shyness-Class Papers, 1999 (Box 161, Folder 28)
    - Social Psychology (Box 161, Folder 29)
    - Student Papers (Box 161, Folder 30)
    - Grades-001, 104, 124, 314, 275, 257A, 1981-1982 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - Grades-Psych 001-A, 257A, 188, 275, 280, 104, 1984-1985 (Box 162, Folder 2)
    - HR/Student Information (Box 162, Folder 3)
    - Osofsky, Michael Joseph (Box 162, Folder 4)
    - Osofsky, Michael Joseph-Indep. Study 1. Execution Team, 2. Hospices (Box 162, Folder 5)
    - Osofsky, M. (Box 162, Folder 6)
    - Jaffer, Shaneeda (Box 162, Folder 7)
    - Boyce, Monique N. (Box 162, Folder 8)
    - Dixon, Sonya M. (Box 162, Folder 9)
    - Dressel, Emily-Shyness, 2000 (Box 162, Folder 10)
    - Kamarei, Golbahar (Box 162, Folder 11)
    - Osofsky, M. Human Subjects Protocols, 2001-2002 (Box 162, Folder 12)
    - Reid, Mark William (Box 162, Folder 13)
    - Simmons, Natalie Renee (Box 162, Folder 14)
    - Womg, Natalie Wei-Mun (Box 162, Folder 15)
    - Advisees, 2000-2001 (Box 162, Folder 16)
    - Psych 187 Grades, 2004 (Box 162, Folder 17)
    - Mind Control Class List (Box 162, Folder 18)
    - TP-Family Analysis, 1991 (Box 162, Folder 19)
    - Grades (Box 162, Folder 20)
    - MC 199-Exams, 1993 (Box 162, Folder 21)
    - Grades-Psych 001, 001A, 104, 170, 188, 257, 257A, 802, 1985-1986 (Box 162, Folder 22)
    - Grades-Psych 1, 1A, 104, 188, 257, 802, 1985-1986 (Box 162, Folder 23)
    - The Case of Mr. F. B. (Box 162, Folder 24)
    - Psych. 121 (Box 162, Folder 25)
    - Mind Control - Final and Grades (Box 162, Folder 26)
    - Diary Study, 1989 (Box 162, Folder 27)
    - January Data (Box 162, Folder 28)
    - Sign-Ups Data (Box 162, Folder 29)
    - Nungesser, L. G. (Box 162, Folder 30)
    - Kavaler/Schneider (Box 162, Folder 31)
    - 301 (Box 162, Folder 32)
    - 132 (Box 162, Folder 33)
    - 332 (Box 162, Folder 34)
    - 343 (Box 162, Folder 35)
    - 92 (Box 162, Folder 36)
    - 122 (Box 162, Folder 37)
    - 37 (Box 162, Folder 38)
    - 401 (Box 162, Folder 39)
    - 131 (Box 162, Folder 40)
    - 121 (Box 162, Folder 41)
    - 337 (Box 162, Folder 42)
    - 399 (Box 162, Folder 43)
    - 179 (Box 162, Folder 44)
    - 11 (Box 162, Folder 45)
    - 68 (Box 162, Folder 46)
    - 148 (Box 162, Folder 47)
    - 31 (Box 162, Folder 48)
    - 147 (Box 162, Folder 49)
    - 56 (Box 162, Folder 50)
    - 51 (Box 162, Folder 51)
    - 44 (Box 162, Folder 52)
    - 48 (Box 162, Folder 53)
    - 97 (Box 162, Folder 54)
    - 314 (Box 162, Folder 55)
    - 361 (Box 162, Folder 56)
    - 351 (Box 162, Folder 57)
    - 58 (Box 162, Folder 58)
    - 36 (Box 162, Folder 59)
    - 46 (Box 162, Folder 60)
    - 16 (Box 162, Folder 61)
    - 318 (Box 162, Folder 62)
    - 308 (Box 162, Folder 63)
    - 145 (Box 162, Folder 64)
    - 26 (Box 162, Folder 65)
    - Sign-Ups/Write-Ups (Box 162, Folder 66)
    - Espt. Sign Up Sheets (Box 162, Folder 67)
    - TPI-Winter, 1988-1989 (Box 162, Folder 68)
  - Medical, Legal, SSN
    Materials in this subseries are restricted due to privacy concerns regarding medical or legal information in accordance with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA). Additionally, some files also include personal social security numbers.
    - Abu Taguba (Box 163, Folder 1)
    - Personal-Rose's Stories (Box 163, Folder 2)
    - Unexplained Arousal Study (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Research Papers-Social Security Numbers (Box 163, Folder 4)
    - A Case of Multiple Personalities-Allison (Box 163, Folder 5)
    - Case Study-Depression Julie (Box 163, Folder 6)
    - Friedman, Patricia (Box 163, Folder 7)
    - Jindra, Gustav (Box 163, Folder 8)
    - Mayberg, Phyllis (Box 163, Folder 9)
    - McCann, Kathy (Box 163, Folder 10)
    - McDowell, Steven (Box 163, Folder 11)
    - Osmond, June (Box 163, Folder 12)
    - Shodnik, Gail (Box 163, Folder 13)
    - M M P P-Roche (Box 163, Folder 14)
    - Gp. 31 (Box 163, Folder 15)
    - Gp. 32 (Box 163, Folder 16)
    - Gp. 33 (Box 163, Folder 17)
    - Gp. 34 (Box 163, Folder 18)
    - Shyness Clinic - Patient Evaluations (1 of 2) (Box 163, Folder 19)
    - Shyness Clinic - Patient Evaluations (2 of 2) (Box 163, Folder 20)
    - Medical History Forms (Box 163, Folder 21)
    - Medical Forms (Box 163, Folder 22)
    - Baldwin, Julie (Box 163, Folder 23)
    - Deindividuation (Box 163, Folder 24)
    - Individuation-Wicklund/Duval (Box 163, Folder 25)
    - Zimbardo/Linsenmeier Grant Final Report, 1983 Jan (Box 163, Folder 26)
    - ONR (Box 163, Folder 27)
    - Action - ONR Research (Box 163, Folder 28)
    - AIDS Research (Box 163, Folder 29)
    - Case Material-V.A. (Box 163, Folder 30)
    - Stanford Soledad Teaching Project (Box 163, Folder 31)
    - Louise Ogborn vs. McDonald's Corp. et al Mark Ford, Attorney, Confidentiality Agreement, 301 (Box 163, Folder 32)
    - Raise Requests (Box 163, Folder 33)
    - Prison Life Study-Applicants not used, background data, interview forms (Box 163, Folder 34)
- Additional materials, Accession ARCH-2016-126
  - Quiet Rage: The Stanford Prison Experiment, 1992; 2016-126.01; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Human Behavior experiments Al Bandura from Phil Zimbardo, 2006-6; 2016-126.02; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - NS 4133 Human Behavior Experiment Dr. Philip Zimbardo, 2006-7-20; 2016-126.03; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Quiet Rage: The Stanford Prison Experiment, undated; 2016-126.04; 1 betacam / betacamsp (Box 1)
- Additional materials, Accession ARCH-2017-005
  - Stanford Prison Experiment slides, 1971 (Box 1)
- Additional materials, Accession ARCH-2017-162
  - The Elephant in the Room: It's time we talked openly about Donald Trump's mental health, 2017 Feb (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Effects of Threat of Surveillance and Actual Surveillance on Expressed Opinions toward Marijuana" by GL White & PGZ, Journal of Social Psychology, 1980 Jun (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Le Cercle Psy" magazine, 2016 Sep/Oct/Nov (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "I want you to become an everyday hero" poster, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Heroic Imagination Project - education impact report, 2015-2016 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Heroic Imagination Project - booklet, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional materials, Accession ARCH-2017-310
  - Reprints, 1973-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Lecture: Putting Life in Your Psychology and Psychology in Your Life, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 10 Principles of Demonstrations in Lectures, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Intro to Psych, 1997 Spring (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Practicum in Teaching, Psych 281, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Psi Chi Newsletter, 1995 Winter (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Discovering Psychology Video Series workbook, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Das Experiment", 2001 Apr 3; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - Posters from speaking engagements (Italy, Poland), circa 2000s (Box 2)